# Ali Hassan

alizhassan199@gmail.com • (310) 359-2873

https://rydalisdarx.github.io/Ali-Personal-Portfolio/ https://www.linkedin.com/in/ali-hassan199/

#### **Objective**

Recent graduate with a degree in Computer Science specializing in Software Engineering with 2+ years of experience from UC Irvine. Fast learner, follows instruction, asks questions. Aims to create responsive and optimal software that provides solutions to issues that affect all users. Always eager to apply my studies in programming and design with a dynamic, diverse team.

#### **Skills**

- **Programming**: C/C++, C#, Python, Java, Javascript, HTML, CSS, SQL, React, Angular.JS
- Software: Visual Studio, Slack, Git, JIRA, Figma, Miro, Photoshop, Microsoft Office 365, Acrobat, ChatGPT
- **Industry Knowledge:** Agile/Scrum, Cloud Computing (AWS, Azure), Graphic Design, Web Design, Machine Learning, Networking, RESTful, Usability Testing, UI/UX Design, Databases, Linux/Unix/Windows OS

# **Work Experience**

# **Software Engineer & Technical Intern**

6/2023-9/2023

M-Theory Group

- Handled 50+ client and customer calls daily, logging tickets, identifying requests, and transferring calls.
- Automated and organized ticketing systems and inventories, removing waste and redundant tickets.
- Collaborated with tech teams to configure and network over 100 computers for hospitals and schools.

# **Extracurricular Activities**

# **Software Engineer**

9/2022-6/2024

Video Game Development Club, UC Irvine

- Focused on making applications with many teams on 10-week projects in C#/C++ focusing on user experience.
- Maintained documents and iterated through prototypes, organized scrum meetings, and took meeting notes.

#### **Dungeons & Dragons Event Organizer**

9/2019-6/2024

Tabletop and Board Game Club, West Los Angeles College & UC Irvine

- Scheduled, hosted, and led weekly Dungeons and Dragons sessions with up to 50+ different players.
- Collaborated with many groups within a shared narrative in a fast-paced environment.

## **Projects**

#### **Neon Rhythm**

9/2023-3/2024

Rhythm Game, created with C# and C++

- Created upcoming note UI, UI showing rhythm judgement line following song BPM, and song beatmaps.
- Structured user flow with responsive menus and interfaces, along with programming menu functionality.
- Saved settings data between play sessions and serialized high scores encouraging more playtime.

#### Turpentine VR

9/2023-12/2023

Decision-Based Immersive Simulation VR Game, created with C# and C++

- Worked in a VR environment, creating in-game physics to account for player actions and mistakes.
- Promoted environmentalism and "thinking green" by using in-game environmental storytelling within UI
- Created UI to keep users immersed within the game world without compromising effectiveness.

## **Bread Project**

1/2023-3/2023

Multiplayer Survival Game, created with C# and C++

- Networked users using Photon, handling disconnections, and ensuring game instance syncs between users.
- Built an interface that connects and reflects changes between user's health as it changes during connection.
- Coded an expandable inventory system that shares resources among users while making real-time updates.

#### **Education**

#### **B.S.** Computer Science, UC Irvine

2022-2024

Relevant Coursework: Adv. C++, Data Structures, Data Management, AI & Machine Learning, Linear Algebra

## A.S. Computer Science, West LA College